#  Release   Plan
The   team   has   one   goal   this   week
:  turn   a   working   narration   path   into   something   a   creator
can   trust .  The   upload   step   should   be   quiet ,  predictable
,  and   honest   about   what   is   happening .
##  What   changes   for
the   creator
They   paste   the   whole   script   once .  They
choose   a   voice .  They   press   generate ,  then   they   get
final   audio   and   subtitle-ready   timing   without   manual   chunking .
-  First
,  the   system   checks   whether   the   script   is   readable .
-  Next
,  it   keeps   the   original   words   intact .
-  Then ,  it   adds
only   structural   pauses   between   sections .
-  Finally ,  it   records   evidence
so   a   reviewer   can   see   what   happened .
##  What   we
still   will   not   promise
We   will   not   claim   full
multilingual   readiness   today .  We   will   not   expose   provider   controls
in   the   browser .  We   will   not   sell   broad   public
export   features   before   the   first   gate   is   stable .
That
is   the   discipline :  fewer   promises ,  better   receipts ,  and   narration
that   sounds   deliberate   instead   of   rushed .